<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Star Base Cafe (Posts about podcast)</title><link>https://rillw.github.io/rillw/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://rillw.github.io/rillw/categories/podcast.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2022 &lt;a href="mailto:starbasecafe@gmail.com"&gt;Rill&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 16:50:41 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Why I Am Doing This Podcast</title><link>https://rillw.github.io/rillw/posts/why-i-am-doing-this-podcast/</link><dc:creator>Rill</dc:creator><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://anchor.fm/rill-w/embed/episodes/Why-I-Am-Doing-This-Podcast-e1hrvfc" height="102px" width="400px" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Transcript&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to The Star Base Cafe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello, this is Rill, and you are listening to Episode One: Why I am
doing this podcast&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a while back, I think it was 2006 I found out about
&lt;a href="https://www.nanowrimo.org/"&gt;NanoWriMo&lt;/a&gt; National Novel Writing Month.
And in 2006, I couldn't participate. But at the beginning of 2007, I
started writing, trying to write with the National Novel Writing Month
principles of just write, don't edit, just keep going. I didn't quite
finish a novel. But later that year, I finished a novel. And year
after year, I wrote a novel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;, introducing some of the same characters and developing a storyline.
But no matter how hard I have tried, I can't go back to the original
novel and finish it. And I can't seem to edit any of the other novels
to make them useful. And yet, I still keep thinking about the novels and
the characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I have begun to wonder if I'm not a novelist, but that I am a person
who likes to tell stories. And I like to think about stories and try to
work out their plot and what people are doing. It's all the other
connected stuff that I'm not very good at.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I thought it might be fun to start this podcast and imagine that we
are at a cafe. I have set this :cafe in a fictional seaside town called
not surprisingly Ril, because some online folks started to tease me that
I was a seaside town in Wales, because apparently, there is such a town.
Although its spelled r h y l, where I spell Rill R i l l. So I started
to run with that and just try to think about the sounds and the
appointments of the fictional seaside town of Rill. And then I thought
this seaside town should have a cafe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I've always liked the idea of calling a place, the star base cafe,
even though we are not somewhere out there in the galaxy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;22&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;orbiting a planet or a strange star or a strange moon. It's all part of
the fiction. I also thought from time to time, the characters I have
thought about and been friends with all these years could appear after
all, their fiction too. So why can't a fictional character come to a
fictional cafe in a fictional seaside town? You see how this works?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The segments of this podcast may be short, may be long, may be frequent,
may be infrequent. We'll just see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may give you a peek into my real life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk to you later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I transcribed this using &lt;a href="https://otter.ai"&gt;otter.ai&lt;/a&gt;and I have cleaned
it up where necessary but I have made no effort to turn this into a
proper essay.&lt;/p&gt;</description><category>podcast</category><guid>https://rillw.github.io/rillw/posts/why-i-am-doing-this-podcast/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 20:59:56 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>